<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hashicorp on Open Source Business Community</title>
    <link>https://opensourcebusiness.community/tags/hashicorp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hashicorp on Open Source Business Community</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2023 Open Source Business Community</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://opensourcebusiness.community/tags/hashicorp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Communities &amp; Scaling Open Source Startups with Jana Iris</title>
      <link>https://opensourcebusiness.community/podcasts/hacking_open_source_business_ep23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opensourcebusiness.community/podcasts/hacking_open_source_business_ep23/</guid>
      <description>Transcription In this episode:
The importance of community building in open source and tech ventures. How to navigate the challenges and rewards of early-stage startups. The long game of building a community and balancing sustainable growth. Monetizing open source by knowing your niche audience and being intentional. Utilizing user feedback to develop features worth paying for. Identifying key users and personas for effective feedback programs. How to measure community value and ROI.</description>
      <content>&lt;h3 id=&#34;transcription&#34;&gt;Transcription &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this episode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The importance of community building in open source and tech ventures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to navigate the challenges and rewards of early-stage startups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The long game of building a community and balancing sustainable growth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monetizing open source by knowing your niche audience and being intentional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilizing user feedback to develop features worth paying for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifying key users and personas for effective feedback programs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to measure community value and ROI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluating early-stage startups through various metrics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go-to-market strategies and community building for transitioning open source projects into businesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing opportunities based on passion and embracing career pivots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The significance of continuous learning, patience, and trusting the process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
