<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DevRel on Open Source Business Community</title>
    <link>https://opensourcebusiness.community/tags/devrel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DevRel on Open Source Business Community</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2023 Open Source Business Community</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://opensourcebusiness.community/tags/devrel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DevRel in Open Source - Strategies, Challenges, and Growth w/ Joe Karlsson - EP. 27</title>
      <link>https://opensourcebusiness.community/podcasts/hacking_open_source_business_ep27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opensourcebusiness.community/podcasts/hacking_open_source_business_ep27/</guid>
      <description>Transcription In this episode:
00:58 - Navigating lay-offs in tech and advice for those going through it 03:24 - The challenges of measuring ROI in DevRel 07:10 - The difference between users and customers in Open Source Businesses 09:22 - The divide between community and business in open source and what to prioritize 15:21 - The open source flywheel and DevRel content strategy 21:09 - Small communities in open source and growing your audience 24:28 - How to Balance High-Pop and Solution-Focused Content 31:20 - Vanity metrics vs.</description>
      <content>&lt;h3 id=&#34;transcription&#34;&gt;Transcription &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this episode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;00:58 -  Navigating lay-offs in tech and advice for those going through it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;03:24 - The challenges of measuring ROI in DevRel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;07:10 - The difference between users and customers in Open Source Businesses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;09:22 - The divide between community and business in open source and what to prioritize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15:21 - The open source flywheel and DevRel content strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;21:09 - Small communities in open source and growing your audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;24:28 - How to Balance High-Pop and Solution-Focused Content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;31:20 - Vanity metrics vs. The metrics that matter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;32:39 - Balancing between different types of target audiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;35:31 - Joe Karlsson&amp;rsquo;s first steps in DevRel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;37:04 - What it takes to get a job in DevRel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;39:58 - Interview tips for Dev Rel job positions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;43:25 - Analyzing TinyBird&amp;rsquo;s open source contributions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;44:52 - Rapid fire questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Adoption, DevRel, and FOSS: Learning from Apache Cassandra - EP. 26 HOSB Podcast</title>
      <link>https://opensourcebusiness.community/podcasts/hacking_open_source_business_ep26/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opensourcebusiness.community/podcasts/hacking_open_source_business_ep26/</guid>
      <description>Transcription In this episode:
His time working in open source database community, including Apache Cassandra&amp;rsquo;s journey and upcoming developments. The role of evangelism and contributors in driving adoption and getting people to try your project. The challenges and mistakes companies make when commercializing open source, with lessons he has learned from his time in the database community. How new features are chosen based on his experience with Cassandra highlighting features such as transactions and open-source tool Guardrails?</description>
      <content>&lt;h3 id=&#34;transcription&#34;&gt;Transcription &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this episode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;His time working in open source database community, including Apache Cassandra&amp;rsquo;s journey and upcoming developments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The role of evangelism and contributors in driving adoption and getting people to try your project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The challenges and mistakes companies make when commercializing open source, with lessons he has learned from his time in the database community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How new features are chosen based on his experience with Cassandra highlighting features such as transactions and open-source tool Guardrails?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does open source innovation slow down as products mature?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is cloud-native anyways?  And what does it mean in the database context?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building a diverse and gloabl team by building trust.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DevRel Best practices includeing, how do you measuring DevRel success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Communities &amp; Scaling Open Source Startups with Jana Iris</title>
      <link>https://opensourcebusiness.community/podcasts/hacking_open_source_business_ep23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://opensourcebusiness.community/podcasts/hacking_open_source_business_ep23/</guid>
      <description>Transcription In this episode:
The importance of community building in open source and tech ventures. How to navigate the challenges and rewards of early-stage startups. The long game of building a community and balancing sustainable growth. Monetizing open source by knowing your niche audience and being intentional. Utilizing user feedback to develop features worth paying for. Identifying key users and personas for effective feedback programs. How to measure community value and ROI.</description>
      <content>&lt;h3 id=&#34;transcription&#34;&gt;Transcription &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this episode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The importance of community building in open source and tech ventures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to navigate the challenges and rewards of early-stage startups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The long game of building a community and balancing sustainable growth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monetizing open source by knowing your niche audience and being intentional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilizing user feedback to develop features worth paying for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifying key users and personas for effective feedback programs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to measure community value and ROI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluating early-stage startups through various metrics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go-to-market strategies and community building for transitioning open source projects into businesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing opportunities based on passion and embracing career pivots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The significance of continuous learning, patience, and trusting the process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
